[music]
Hello everyone and
welcome back to another
edition here at English
Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine
and today we've got a great
upper intermediate level lesson for
you all about animal and human rights.
Right. So it's a very
debatable topic people
want to protect animals,
mistreatment of animals.
And this is what we're
going to talk about
today, protecting animals
and giving them rights.
Do you think animals have rights?
Eh, well, you know, I think
we can leave that for the end.
I don't want to, you know, influence
the argument here in today's dialogue.
But yeah, as you've
said, I think it's very
much a topic that people
can go both ways on.
So why don't we listen to our
dialogue as two people discuss
animal rights and let's
get their opinions on things.
[music]
You should have seen a TV
show that was on last night.
The topic it covered was
really interesting, animal rights.
Do you really believe in that?
If they're going to focus on something,
they should do it on civil rights.
Yes, but we can't deny
that animals are vulnerable,
defenseless, and are completely
at the mercy of human beings.
I understand your point, but we continue to
have transgressions against human rights.
If so much attention weren't
devoted to the topic of animals,
we would then concentrate more on saving a
human being instead of protecting a koala.
You can't compare apples and oranges.
I believe that both topics are
important and that we can't ignore them.
The mistreatment of animals can
cause a great environmental imbalance.
I believe that governments should
prohibit activities like poaching.
Well, you are right on that point.
This is the reason that I don't buy leather
and I try to buy synthetic products.
At least you're doing your part.
My contribution is to
have a pet in the house
that I treat like a
member of the family.
As long as you don't treat it
better than your wife, it's fine.
We're back and both of
them have good points, right?
Favorite and against.
As you said, they
also talk about human
rights, which is also a
very important topic.
But before we discuss this
topic, why don't we take a look
at the language that was used
now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Alright, so in language takeaway,
our first word today is vulnerable.
Okay, vulnerable is a great word.
It's a way to describe
something and so something
is vulnerable if it can't
really protect itself.
So you are in danger of being hurt.
Exactly.
Right, so you're vulnerable.
Now, this isn't only
used for animals, right?
It can be like an army
is vulnerable if they
don't have strong
defenses on the borders.
Right, or my emotions.
I'm feeling vulnerable
because I just had really horrible
week and I'm really depressed
and I'm emotionally vulnerable.
Okay, very good.
So vulnerable and they also talked
about transgressions against human rights.
Alright, so a transgression is a thing.
It's a noun and a
transgression is like doing
something harmful to or
against someone or something.
So a transgression, it's a noun, so
is it doing something in a bad way?
Exactly.
It's a bad thing.
It's always negative.
Exactly.
It's not positive, right?
Right.
And so in many prayers, for example, in the
Christian faith, you say, you know, Lord, forgive me
for my transgressions for having kind of crossed
the line from doing good things to bad things.
So you're doing bad things.
Very good.
So that's a good way
of putting it to cross
the line to kind of go
beyond where you should.
Alright, so transgressions.
And now another very serious
problem in the world is poaching.
That's one of the things that they
said they should control poaching.
Alright, you might have
heard this word in a different
context because it does
have another meaning,
but I'm just going to explain the one
meaning here that we're talking about, which
is killing animals, especially for sport
or for selling their skins and their first.
Right.
So that's poaching.
What's the difference
between poaching and hunting?
Hunting can be legal.
Poaching is illegal.
Okay.
So that's the main difference.
Hunting is usually for sport, you
hunt either for food or for sport, right?
Legal hunting.
But poaching is
usually you want to sell,
like you said, the fur
or the skins or stuff.
Or the tusks on rhinos
or something like that.
Exactly.
Alright, so poaching.
And then they talked
about synthetic products.
So what is a synthetic product?
Well, synthetic product is
something that is man-made.
So it's not natural in that it
doesn't come from the earth.
Cotton is a natural product.
And plastic for example is
synthetic or another example.
Nylon.
Nylon is a really good synthetic product.
And so people who don't
want to use animal products like
wool or leather, they prefer
to use synthetic products.
And I think maybe you've
heard this in clothing.
It's called synthetic fibers, right?
Like nylon or polyester.
Exactly.
These are all the words that we
have for language takeaway today.
So why don't we move
on now to a couple of very
interesting phrases that
we saw in the dialogue.
Now influence your builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay, this first phrase is,
well, it's a common one, but
it's definitely not used in
very happy circumstances.
We say that something or someone
is at the mercy of someone else.
Okay, so animals are at
the mercy of human beings.
What does this mean exactly?
Mercy.
So basically, it means
that the animals in this
case don't have control
of what's going on.
So human beings are the
ones that control everything.
So if I decide to kill them, then they
are at my mercy, at my will, at my whim.
Exactly.
And so you could say,
I'm at your mercy, Marco.
Please just like help me out with this.
It's like you're the one in control.
You're the one who can help the situation.
Will you help?
Exactly.
I'm at the mercy of someone.
And then they were talking
and debating this thing.
And an interesting comparison came
up, you can't compare apples and oranges.
All right, you're going to
hit us all the time in English.
It's not just a funny little
phrase that the person uses.
It's a very common idiom.
And so we say, it's
like apples and oranges.
Or you can't compare apples and oranges.
And this is essentially saying,
these are two different things.
Completely different.
So I can't compare him and her
because it's apples and oranges.
They're two different
things, two different people.
Right.
Because that's what in the movie
you said they were like peas and carrots.
It's just go together.
Does that make sense?
No, really.
This gum was a little
bit strange like that.
But I think the meaning
is that if I say that's a big
apple and I say, that's a
small apple, they're all apples.
So I can compare them.
But I say, this is a really big orange.
And that's a really big apple.
Well, they're different.
They're different.
You just can't compare them.
All right.
And towards the end, the person
said that you're doing your part.
You're doing your part.
So this is a hard one to
understand sometimes
because it's not
like a part in a play.
It's more like a part in society.
You're helping make society
or culture or civilization better.
So you're contributing.
Exactly.
For example, what would be an example of
a person doing their part towards society?
Well, for example, I don't own a car.
I ride my bike.
And it's my way of doing my
part to help the environment.
Okay, very good.
Because I can't obviously, I can't buy
a factory that's, you know, very green.
Or I can't do all these
things to change the world.
So I'm going to do small things that's
that those are my way of doing my part.
Okay.
So like another example would
be recycling that's doing your part.
Exactly.
Or in this case, the
person bought only
synthetic products,
nothing made from nature.
All right.
Very good.
So very interesting phrases.
Why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the last time?
And then we'll be right back.
You should have seen a TV
show that was on last night.
The topic it covered
was really interesting.
Animal rights.
Do you really believe in that?
If they're going to focus on something,
they should do it on civil rights.
Yes, but we can't deny
that animals are vulnerable,
defenseless, and are completely
at the mercy of human beings.
I understand your point, but we continue to
have transgressions against human rights.
If so much attention weren't
devoted to the topic of animals,
we would then concentrate more on saving a
human being instead of protecting a koala.
You can't compare apples and oranges.
I believe that both topics are
important and that we can't ignore them.
The mistreatment of animals can
cause a great environmental imbalance.
I believe that governments should
prohibit activities like poaching.
Well, you are right on that point.
This is the reason that I don't buy leather,
and I try to buy synthetic products.
At least you're doing your part.
My contribution is to
have a pet in the house
that I treat like a
member of the family.
As long as you don't treat it
better than your wife, it's fine.
All right, so a debatable
topic, animals and animal rights.
What do you think?
Well, I'll say this.
I would be a hypocrite
if I said that it's bad
to hurt animals because
I meet a meat eater.
I like to eat meat and
I like to wear leather,
but I do think it's bad
to mistreat animals.
I really try to buy
free-range chicken or meat
from places I know that
treat the animals well.
I definitely disagree with
poaching and with using animals,
especially in danger animals,
for money and cash purposes.
That's my position, but what's yours?
I mean, I know you eat meat too.
No, yeah, of course.
I think even though protection of
animals is a very important topic.
You don't want the
mistreatment of these little
creatures that are very vulnerable to us,
because we're smarter than them in the end.
But I think also it has to
do a lot with superstition
sometimes and kind of
mystical and magical things.
For example, people killing
rhinos because they believe
that the rhino horn has
amazing curing properties,
or the same thing with
elephant tusks and stuff like that.
It involves a certain aspect that
people almost don't know any better.
They truly believe that these things
actually work or that they will help them.
So they don't consider the
dialogue set, the imbalance
that they create in the
environment or the consequences.
Or there might be some
very serious evolutionary
consequences that we
cannot even imagine.
Things change kind of over
time sometimes quickly and
sometimes slowly, but if we
force change really quickly,
who knows what the results are going
to be, it might be really negative for us.
Exactly, and that's what
we want to know now.
What do you think about
these topics, because in the
end the environment
animals, they're all connected.
If you wipe out all the
foxes in a forest and you're
going to have too many
snakes running around, right?
Yeah. So what do you
think? Come to EnglishPod.
com and where you can leave
all your questions, comments,
or suggestions, and we're
always there to help out.
So we hope to see you there, and
until next time everyone, goodbye.
Bye.
(upbeat music)